export const GEOGRAPHYA2008 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The scale of the map as a statement is",
A: "1 cm represent 1/4 km",
B: "1cm represents 1/2 km",
C: "1 cm represents 1 km",
D: "1 cm represents 2 km",
answer: "B. 1cm represents ½ km",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The actual distance from Ega to Buka as the crow flies approximately",
A: "4.5 km",
B: "8.0 km",
C: "10.0km",
D: "18.0km",
answer: "A. 4.5 km",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The bearing of Buka from Muba is approximately",
A: "100°",
B: "150°",
C: "200°",
D: "230°",
answer: "D. 230°",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The actual distance from Muba to OMOBI along the road is",
A: "4km",
B: "5km",
C: "6km",
D: "12km",
answer: "C. 6km",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Which of the following settlement is visible from Muba?",
A: "Ega",
B: "Omobi",
C: "Opula",
D: "Koba",
answer: "D. Koba",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. If the map is reduced half its size, what will be the scale of the reduced map?",
A: "1:25,000",
B: "1:50,000",
C: "1:100,000",
D: "1:150,000",
answer: "C. 1:100,000",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The footpath from Ega to Ruku passes through a",
A: "Valley",
B: "Plane",
C: "Saddle",
D: "Mountain peak",
answer: "C. Saddle",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The feature at the Northeastern part of the map is called",
A: "Knoll",
B: "Cone",
C: "Ridge",
D: "Valley",
answer: "C. Ridge",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. What is the likely occupation of the people in the mapped area?",
A: "Fishing",
B: "Mining",
C: "Farming",
D: "Farming",
answer: "C. Farming",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. What is the dominant vegetation in the South Western part of the map?",
A: "Forest",
B: "Grass",
C: "Scrub",
D: "Montane vegetation",
answer: "A. Forest",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Which month has the lowest temperature?",
A: "February",
B: "April",
C: "June",
D: "July",
answer: "D. July",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The month with the highest rainfall is",
A: "January",
B: "June",
C: "July",
D: "December",
answer: "B. June",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The body at the centre of the solar system is",
A: "Earth",
B: "Sun",
C: "Jupiter",
D: "Pluto",
answer: "B. Sun",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. The farthest planet in the solar system is The",
A: "Saturn",
B: "Mars",
C: "Jupiter",
D: "Pluto",
answer: "D. Pluto",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Which of the following is not a proof that the earth is spherical in shape?",
A: "Circumnavigation of the earth.",
B: "Rise and fall of tide.",
C: "Sunrise and sunset",
D: "Circular horizon.",
answer: "B. Rise and fall of tide.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. The Tropical Regions of the world lie within",
A: "66½ ° to 90° North and South of the Equator",
B: "0° to 66½° Equator North and South of the Equator",
C: "0° to 23 ½°  North and South of the Equator",
D: "23½° to 90° North and South of the Equator",
answer: "C. 0° to 23½ North and South of the Equator",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. If the local time in station Y, longitude 20o E is 8:00 am, what is the local time in station Z on longitude 35oE?",
A: "4.20 am",
B: "5.50 am",
C: "6.20 am",
D: "7.50 am",
answer: "A. 4.20 am",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. They are stratified, contain fossils and are non—crystalline. This statement best describes",
A: "Igneous rocks",
B: "Metamorphic rocks.",
C: "Volcanic rocks.",
D: "Sedimentary rocks.",
answer: "D. Sedimentary rocks.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. In the process of metamorphism, limestone is changed into",
A: "Quartzite.",
B: "Gneiss",
C: "Marble.",
D: "Graphite.",
answer: "C. Marble.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The gradual disintegration of rocks which are exposed on the earth’s surface is",
A: "Denudation.",
B: "Erosion.",
C: "Weathering",
D: "Deposition.",
answer: "C. Weathering",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The alternate contraction and expansion of rocks due to repeated temperature changes resulting in rock disintegration is called",
A: "Exfoliation.",
B: "Oxidation",
C: "Hydration.",
D: "Hydrolysis.",
answer: "A. Exfoliation.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Which of the following is not a product of wind erosion?",
A: "Rock pedestal.",
B: "Loess.",
C: "Yardangs.",
D: "Zeugens.",
answer: "B. Loess.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Granite when metamorphosed, give rise to",
A: "Diorite.",
B: "Gneiss",
C: "Graphite.",
D: "Marble.",
answer: "B. Gneiss",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Which of the following is a mountain of denudation?",
A: "Block Mountain.",
B: "Residual Mountain.",
C: "Intermont Plateau.",
D: "Fold Mountain.",
answer: "B. Residual Mountain.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. A lunar eclipse takes place when the",
A: "Sun comes between the earth and the moon.",
B: "Moon conies between the sun and earth.",
C: "Earth conies between the sun and the moon.",
D: "Earth and moon are on either side of the sun.",
answer: "C. Earth conies between the sun and the moon.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Rift valleys are unique features associated with",
A: "Residual mountains.",
B: "Volcanic mountains.",
C: "Block mountains.",
D: "Fold mountains.",
answer: "C. Block mountains.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Saucer—shaped volcanic intrusions form",
A: "Lapolith",
B: "Dyke",
C: "Bathol iths.",
D: "Sill.",
answer: "A. Lapolith",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. One major process of chemical weathering Is",
A: "Hydrolysis",
B: "Frost action.",
C: "Exfoliation.",
D: "Rock shattering.",
answer: "A. Hydrolysis",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The drainage pattern shown in the figure above is",
A: "Centripetal",
B: "Radial",
C: "Trellis",
D: "annular",
answer: "C. Trellis",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. The stream marked A can be described as",
A: "Consequent stream.",
B: "Resequent stream",
C: "Subsequent stream",
D: "Insequent stream.",
answer: "A. Consequent stream.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Which of the following is a feature of the middle course of a river?",
A: "Rapids and falls.",
B: "Interlocking spurs.",
C: "Levee",
D: "Flood plain.",
answer: "B. Interlocking spurs.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The order of the three closely related activities of rivers is",
A: "Erosion, deposition, transportation.",
B: "Transportation, deposition, erosion.",
C: "Erosion, transportation, deposition.",
D: "Deposition,.erosion, transportation.",
answer: "C. Erosion, transportation, deposition.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. . Favourable factors for lumbering include all the following except:",
A: "Presence of dense tropical rainforest.",
B: "Presence of market.",
C: "Absence of many economic trees.",
D: "High demand for hard wood.",
answer: "C. Absence of many economic trees.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. One of the contributions of irrigation schemes to economic development is",
A: "Increased growth of water weeds.",
B: "Increased production of industrial raw materials.",
C: "Breeding of disease-carrying insects",
D: "Displacement of settlements.",
answer: "B. Increased production of industrial raw materials.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. One advantage of bush fallowing is that",
A: "Leads to wastage of land.",
B: "Aids natural restoration of soil nutrients.",
C: "Leads to land fragmentation.",
D: "Destroys valuable forest resources.",
answer: "B. Aids natural restoration of soil nutrients.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Which of the following is a major disadvantage of plantation agriculture?",
A: "Encourages monoculture.",
B: "Regular supply of raw materials.",
C: "Foreign exchange earner.",
D: "Application of modern technology.",
answer: "A. Encourages monoculture.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. A situation where a country has more people than its physical and natural resources can support is described as",
A: "Optimum population",
B: "Overpopulation.",
C: "Under population.",
D: "Maximum population.",
answer: "B. Overpopulation.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. One advantage of low population density is that it results in",
A: "Environmental pollution.",
B: "Traffic congestion.",
C: "Shortage of food.",
D: "Low pressure on social amenities.",
answer: "D. Low pressure on social amenities.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. The population of an area is determined by all the following except",
A: "Births",
B: "Deaths",
C: "Immigration.",
D: "Enumeration.",
answer: "D. Enumeration.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. One major reason for the rapid growth of world population is",
A: "Improved medical care.",
B: "Immigration.",
C: "Religious belief",
D: "Improved transportation network.",
answer: "A. Improved medical care.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. The movement of people from one geographical area to another involving permanent or temporary settlement is called",
A: "Emigration.",
B: "Immigration.",
C: "Migration.",
D: "Translocation.",
answer: "C. Migration.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Which of the following is—not a function of an urban settlement?",
A: "Provision of agricultural products.",
B: "Provision of administrative services.",
C: "Industrial services.",
D: "Socio-cultural centre.",
answer: "A. Provision of agricultural products.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. It has low cost of maintenance, can carry bulky goods over long.distances and is the cheapest means of transportation. This statement best describes",
A: "Road transport",
B: "River transport.",
C: "Ocean transport.",
D: "Air transport.",
answer: "C. Ocean transport.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. The universal mode of transportation is",
A: "Railway",
B: "Road",
C: "Air",
D: "Ropeway",
answer: "B. Road",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. A major consideration in the location of a cement industry is",
A: "Nearness to source of power.",
B: "Proximity to source of raw materials.",
C: "Nearness to market.",
D: "Availability of capital.",
answer: "B. Proximity to source of raw materials.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. One disadvantage of localization of industries is that it",
A: "Creates employment opportunities.",
B: "Causes environmental pollution.",
C: "Leads to the development of organized market.",
D: "Leads to the attraction of subsidiary industries in the area.",
answer: "B. Causes environmental pollution.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. Farmsteads, hamlets and villages are examples of",
A: "Urban settlement.",
B: "Conurbation.",
C: "Megalopolis.",
D: "Rural settlement.",
answer: "D. Rural settlement.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. Himalayas, Rockies, Alps are all examples of",
A: "Horst Mountains.",
B: "Fold Mountains.",
C: "Residual Mountains.",
D: "Volcanic Mountains.",
answer: "B. Fold Mountains.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. One way of increasing the speed of railway system of transportation is to",
A: "Buy new trains.",
B: "Employ fast train drivers.",
C: "Adopt standard gauge.",
D: "Overfund railway system of transportation.",
answer: "C. Adopt standard gauge.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. Which of the following is not an achievement of the ECOWAS?",
A: "Free movement of people.",
B: "Non-implementation of agreed programmes.",
C: "Educational interactions.",
D: "Trade liberalization.",
answer: "B. Non-implementation of agreed programmes.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},


]